Ossama Mohamed Yassin El-Darawy

ALShorouq -Orchid district -Cairo – Egypt Oyd0100@Gmail.com (01227777451)

A highly motivated, accurate, organized and dynamic with experience in the banking sector. Having a diverse background in the banking sector, that taught me to adapt to different perspectives and mindsets, building relationships. Effective at collaborating with stakeholders from different backgrounds to develop a culture of performance and success, always ready to go beyond basics assignments. Quick learner with good computer abilities.

Education

Cairo University -faculty of Economics and Political Science - Bachelor of Economics -English section, Minor: social science computer, Overall grade: Good, Graduation project grade: Very good (2013 –2017) (The Impact of Minimum Wage on Employment)

(The Role of Small and Medium sized Enterprises to Eliminate Poverty in Egypt.)

Experience

Central Bank of Egypt (from July-2022 till now)

Treasury Back Office:

- Join introduction and training for Flex Cube System,
- Trades Processing: verification, matching, settlement and reporting of all trade details executed by the Front Office through a wide range of Financial products (FX, MM, FI, REPO, etc.)
- Service of the MOF Sovereign Eurobonds and local T-bills denominated in foreign currencies.
- Performing operations of Egypt SDR account with the IMF along with IMF accounts with Egypt.
- Publishing Exchange rates (Official & Market rates).
- Cash Management support: Reporting actual Nostro cash balances in addition to the projected cash balance.
- Repo Desk, controlling and execution of all repo events with counter parties (margin call, margin return, price differential, independent amounts and substitution)

National Bank of Egypt (from 2018 to June-2022)

Treasury middle Office- Operations: (FEB 2021to June 2022)

- Join UAT on treasury system introducing new products (Finastra).
- Change procedures for other sectors (Heritage operations)
- Observing and controlling all treasury product between front and back office.
- Nostro desk Cash management for NBE head office and branches.
- Resources and uses report daily & monthly.
- Currency position report.
- Observe and manage ATM (FX transaction) reports with branches.
- Examining scenarios on Flex Cube system for new product with IT operation teams.

Correspondent banks sector – Operations: (January 2018 to February 2021)

- Change strategies and procedures of sector (audit data entry and Vostro accounts departments) and communication with other departments.
- Audit: daily review treasury deals and journal entries.
- Nostro and Vostro accounts department.
- Data entry: general ledgers and shadow accounts.
- Administration and Archiving.

Training at National Bank of Egypt (15-september 2017 / 15-janury 2018)

Correspondent banks operation.

Training at Faisal Islamic Bank (22-July2015 / 22-August2015)

• Foreign Relation Department.

Certificates

- Foundation program at Egyptian Banking Institutes.
- Credit Certificate 2019 at Egyptian Banking Institutes.
- Internal audit principal course at Egyptian Banking Institutes.
- English General Course at AUC
- CECS Level 1 " U16 Coach " Athletics.
- Foundation Sports Coaching certificate.
- ICDL Course

Skills and Achievments

- Good knowledge of Microsoft Office (Excel, word and power point)
- Dedication and Hard Worked/ Networking and Teamwork Player / Accuracy and Time Management/Tolerance of Change and Uncertainty
- Fitness Coach for beginners.
- Diving Trainer in Gezira sports club (beginners, under 11/13 years) (2016-2017) Full time job
- Team Leader Organizer in Arab basketball competition (April 2016)
- Diving Trainer in Zohour sports club (under 11 years) (2015 2016) Full time job
- Vise Head Sports Committee Student Union (October 2015, till 2017)
- Human Resources Committee Member at EBSM (Egyptian Banking System Model (2015)

Date of Birth: 1/1/1995 Marital Status: Married Military status: Exempted